Casey A. LaClair

309 Greenwich Ave, Apt C319, Warwick RI, 02886 casey.a.laclair@gmail.com (401)-327-0646

Information Technology Specialist with six years of experience in satellite communications in the military and as a government contractor, three out of six years were supervisory. Adaptable team player with a reliable work ethic and a great attention to detail. Proficient in Microsoft Outlook, Excel, Word, and PowerPoint.

Technical Proficiencies

Java, Python, SQLite, XML, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JSON, AJAX, Git/Github, Eclipse, Android Studio, Visual Studio

Courses Taken

- Java Programming
- Advanced Java Programming
- Advanced Java Honors (Android Application)
- Machine Learning (Coursera)
- Free Code Camp Front End Dev.
- Statistical Analysis

Professional Experience

Apr 2016- Dec 2016 BAE MILSATCOM Technician (Greenland)

- Conducted troubleshooting, operations, and maintenance of local satellite communications equipment in support of Missile Warning Operations Center, leading to less than .02% downtime,
- Provided troubleshooting and repair services for Defense Satellite Communications System terminals.

2013-2016 MILSTAR Satellite Communications Shift Supervisor (Germany)

- Supervised preventative maintenance and repairs for highly specialized satellite communications equipment.
- Awarded Army Commendation Medal for providing specialized training to personnel across three separate satellite systems, as well as one NATO server network.
- Supervised remote technical support to eight substations throughout Europe on troubleshooting for three systems.
- Received Army Achievement Medal for successfully managing two emergency satellite transitions in support of European Commands, Joint Nuclear Operation Center.

2012-2013 Human Resources Specialist Technical Assistant (Kuwait)

- Awarded Army Commendation Medal for support as a Human Resources Specialist Assistant, ensuring proper records management for the unit through technical solutions.
- Created a local Microsoft Excel spreadsheet that automatically updates with needed information, allowing managers to access updated information independently at any time.

Education & Certifications

- Satellite Communications Training The United States Army Signal School at Fort Gordon, Georgia 2011
- US ARMY Basic Leadership Course Grafenwoehr, Germany 2014
- MILSTAR AN/TRC-194(V)2 EHF Transportable Terminal Training Course
- Free Code Camp Front End Development Certification
- High School Diploma 2010